Fundamentals


------- what is data Science -------
The application of formal science, applied science and data to solve complex problems and make informed decisions

	MY DEFINITION: (The process of extracting meaningful insights from data to make well informed decisions)
	
--------- What is machine learning -------------
The process of learning significant patterns in a set of observations (test) that are represented trough data.

	MY DEFINITION: (The process of using machines to find patterns in the data)

Supervised Machine learning
	Machines are trained on "labelled" training data
		---> labelled data: the input data contains correct output

Unsupervised Machine learning
	Models used "Unlabelled" data to find hidden patterns and insight from data
		---> Unlabelled data: the input contains NO output

Reinforcement Machine Learning
	Feedback based Machine learning where good results are awarded good feedback and bad results are awarded penalties.

------Methods to transforming data into action--------
Statistical analysis:
Regression:
Classification:
Clustering:
Time series analysis:
Anomaly detection:
NLP:
Distributed ML:
Graph analysis:
Recommender systems:
Neural networks/ deep learning: 
	
-------- Data Science pipeline -----------

1. planing
	* Clearly define the scope of the project.
	* define what success is for the project.
	* ask questions, ask the wright questions, ask you own questions.


2. Acquisition
	Create a path from the original data sources to the environment in which you will work with the data.
	(Write a python script to collect and structure the data)


3. Preparation
	Get the data into a format that can be easily explored, analyzed and visualized.

	(Think about what makes the data "massy" and "incorrect")
	

4. Exploration

	identify features that have the largest impact on the target variable (out come)
	(Remove noisy variable)
	
5. Modeling

	Create a robust and generalizable model that is a mapping between features and a target outcome (label)
	* Train, Test

6. Delivery

	Enable others to use what you have learned or developed throughout all the previous stages
	(presentation or report, Notebook/Scripts, dashboards)

7. Maintenance




















